Joey Gryder

△r Mt. Ple

Joey Gryder Mt. Pleasant, SC

Sr. Software Engineer

joey.gryder@gmail.com https://www.joeygryder.com

Sprint Team Technical Lead

Skills

My primary skill set is centered around back-end development, having multiple years of experience in C# and .NET Framework. I've designed and implemented applications such as high performance web services, concurrent workloads in AWS Lambda, and Dockerized distributed worker services in ECS. I also have experience with relational databases and NoSQL technologies, with much of my career spent utilizing MS SQL Server and MongoDB.

Experience

BoomTown ROI / Sr. Software Engineer - Technical Lead

MAY 2018 - PRESENT, CHARLESTON, SC

Serve as my team's Technical Lead, acting as a mentor for multiple associate and mid-level engineers. As a lead, I am the primary development liaison and can effectively communicate with everyone from junior engineers to Product owners, up through to our architects and C-level executives.

Act in a scrum master capacity, reinforcing strong agile methodologies with my teams.

Develop and maintain some of the most mission critical portions of the BoomTown tech stack, including but not limited to: data ingest of home listings, email notifications, and central SNS/SQS-based messaging subsystems.

Member of 'Foundation' architecture council, responsible for design and review of all major development projects across the organization.

Lead an infrastructure Environment Committee with representatives from multiple sprint teams, to assign projects out to the department to reinforce cost-effective hosting practices. To date, the committee has identified and implemented changes to save tens of thousands of dollars in annual hosting costs.

BoomTown ROI / Sr. Software Engineer in Test - QA Technical Lead

AUGUST 2014 - MAY 2018, CHARLESTON, SC

Architected and implemented the first test automation framework at BoomTown, built with Cucumber, React, and Selenium WebDriver.

Helped grow the QA engineering team from two initial SETs to a staff of over ten engineers.

Blackbaud / Sr. Software Quality Engineer

JUNE 2011 - AUGUST 2014, CHARLESTON, SC

 $Built\ a\ Bootstrap\ /\ jQuery\ /\ MVC. NET\ testing\ dashboard\ to\ allow\ for\ the\ execution\ and\ storage\ of\ test\ automation\ results.$

Implemented an in-house mobile application testing lab using Selenium Grid, Appium, and various iOS and Android devices.

Education

Appalachian State University / B.S. in Computer Science

JANUARY 2009 - MAY 2011, BOONE, NC Summa Cum Laude

UNC Asheville / B.A. in Political Science

AUGUST 2003 - MAY 2007, ASHEVILLE, NC